-I said I don't know anything! -Wait.
-就說我不知道了 -等等
-Don't touch me. -Hold him down!
-別碰我 -抓住他
-Hey… Let go of me! Hey! -Handcuff him!
-喂，放開我，喂
I said I didn't do anything!
就說我什麼都沒做了
A 21-year-old male was arrested for breaking into
闖入位於東京旭市超商
a convenience store in Asahi City, Tokyo, and stealing cash.
搶奪現金的21歲男子已遭警方逮捕
CONVENIENCE STORE ROBBERY MAN ARRESTED - STAFF MEMBER INJURED
（超商強盜案，男子已遭逮捕）
The man arrested for robbery causing injury is Tokyo's--
因強盜傷害罪嫌疑被逮捕的是東京…
This is problematic, Arima.
這可不行啊，有馬
This may be your personal social media account, but this…
就算是你的個人社群網站 但這種發言…
"'Suspect' is a media jargon coined by the press.
“‘嫌疑人’只是媒體 創造出來的報導用語
They treat someone as a criminal even before the trial
經審判前就被當成罪犯
and the way the press reports the news is questionable."
這種報導本身就有問題”
In other words, you're criticizing your peers, right?
你這是在批判自己人吧？
We should be careful when we report any news.
報導應該慎重
As a matter of fact,
實際上警方跟檢方 都有可能做出錯誤判斷
-As the press, we-- -You always say things like this.
-我們媒體… -就是因為你總是這樣說
That's why you're banned from the press club.
才會被記者俱樂部拒於門外
You only follow stories of false charges
只顧著追冤罪受害案件
and haven't gotten any scoop lately.
最近連個獨家都沒拿到
Think carefully about your situation.
你好好想想自己的立場吧
That's all I have to say.
我就言盡於此
Director Senami still disagrees with what you think.
你跟瀨波局長意見還是這麼不合呢
Idiots like him are the reason for reporting bias and trial by media.
就是有那種笨蛋 才會導致偏見跟報導傷害
The suspect, Tokachi, denies charges of robbery.
嫌疑人十勝否認其嫌疑
Of course they won't multiply.
不，根本不可能變多啊
SHIN KUROKAWA
（黑川真，最高檢察廳檢察官次長）
Mr. Kurokawa's father is a public prosecutor?
檢察官？黑川律師的父親是檢察官？
Yes, he's the Deputy Prosecutor-General at the Supreme Public Prosecutors Office.
對，而且是最高檢察廳的檢察官次長
But if so, why…
既然如此，為什麼…
Why is the elite prosecutor's son such a weird, penniless lawyer?
為什麼超菁英檢察官之子 會成為這種不賺錢的怪咖律師？
Well, yeah.
就是啊
If you're curious, why don't you ask him?
有興趣的話就直接問他本人啊
-You're hungry, right? -Yes?
-你肚子也餓了吧？ -什麼？
It's almost time for lunch.
對喔，差不多該吃午餐了
-I'll make some tea. -Thanks.
-我去倒茶 -好
COCOA PEAS
（可可豌豆）
Oh? Kurokawa, you'll have those for lunch today again?
咦？黑川，今天也只吃那些嗎？
It's before payday
因為還沒發薪
and I have to check this regularly and replace them with some new ones.
而且必須不定期確認 包裡的東西，補充新品
Sometimes they might expire.
一不小心就會過期的
You should spend the money on food instead of wasting it on these.
把買那些沒用東西的錢 拿來吃飯不就好了
All the rubbish on your desk is useless too.
你桌上這些破爛也都毫無用處
Calm down.
別這麼說嘛
Your lunch today looks delicious too, Miss Wakura.
和倉律師的便當 今天看起來也很美味呢
You're so young but always cook for yourself.
這麼年輕 卻總是親手做便當，真了不起
I've been doing it just to save money.
只是習慣罷了 我從以前就為了節省而自己帶便當
What? I'm not lovely?
不可愛是什麼意思？
If you're a pretty female lawyer,
長得漂亮的女律師
it's common sense that you shouldn't be able to cook, right?
至少會有廚藝差的弱點 這是常理吧？
That obviously is a prejudice.
這很明顯就是偏見
Your lunch today is modest too,
今天的午餐也很客氣呢 刑事部門的各位
Mr. Noboribetsu, you seem to be in a good mood.
登別律師，你似乎心情很好啊
Well, the CEO of a client company wants to express his gratitude,
剛才我擔任顧問的公司社長 說平時受我們照顧
so he treated every member in the corporate law division
送了菊丹的高級便當
to an expensive lunchbox from Kittan!
給企業法務部門的全體人員喔
That's excellent.
那還真是大方啊
Excuse me. Do you have any lunchboxes left?
請問那些便當會有剩嗎？
No, and if there were, I wouldn't give it to you.
沒剩，有剩也不會分給你
-I guess so. -Mr. Kurokawa,
-也是 -黑川律師
-have mine if you want. -May I?
-不嫌棄的話請用 -可以嗎？
Hey, don't waste it. It's Kittan's lunchbox!
等等，別浪費啊 這可是菊丹的便當喔
I used to have their lunchboxes often before, but lately…
我之前就常吃這間便當 但最近不太想吃
What?
什麼？
It got worse after the son took over, and I don't really like it.
他們換人經營後 味道就變差了，不太合我的胃口
So, Mr. Kurokawa, please have it.
所以黑川律師，請用吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Isawa was born to a pretty rich family.
石和似乎是有錢人家的少爺
That's why he doesn't hesitate when he says something rude.
所以有時候會不經意說出失禮的話
Seriously?
真的假的？
Wow, I have to thank Isawa!
天啊，真是太感謝石和了
I haven't had a proper meal in a long time.
好久沒吃到這麼棒的一餐了
Do you have no dignity, Mr. Kurokawa?
黑川律師，你就沒有尊嚴嗎？
No, and I'm hungry.
沒有，而且我肚子也餓了
Don't say it so decisively.
別這麼老實啊
I mean, you are, in fact…
我是說，黑川律師你其實…
-I am in fact what? -No, I mean, you…
-其實什麼？ -不，就是…
Mr. Kurokawa, you're asked to be someone's duty solicitor.
黑川律師，義務辯護委託
Okay.
是
-Another job that won't earn us money? -Oh no, no, no.
-又是賺不了錢的案子啊？ -等等喔
Thanks.
不好意思
Hello. Kurokawa speaking. I'm the lawyer.
電話換人聽了，我是黑川律師
Yes. Okay, it's fine.
是…沒問題
Please fax me the relevant documents.
那麼相關資料 請傳真給我，是，麻煩了
Kurokawa.
黑川
It's robbery causing injury. After I have lunch--
似乎是強盜傷害罪 吃了午餐後我再…
I'm not talking about that.
不是啦
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry…
不好意思，真的很抱歉，不好意思
-Oh, it's my lunch-- -Thanks for lunch.
-那是我的便當… -我開動了
You're welcome.
請用
Please… help Takeo!
請幫幫岳雄
I'll investigate it thoroughly and defend him.
我會徹底調查，奮戰到底
I think that he is the culprit.
我認為他就是犯人
I really wanted to turn over a new leaf.
我真的是想洗心革面的
Don't be such a baby!
別說這種軟弱的話了
PROVING INNOCENCE IN THE CONVENIENCE STORE CASE!
（洗清超商強盜案的冤罪 再次展開衝擊性的實驗）
-Roger. -We might be able
-是 -這樣或許
to get an alibi for Mr. Tokachi's now!
就能確立十勝先生的不在場證明了
The crime scene
案發現場是 旭市的24小時超商，三津屋
The robbery happened on January 16, 2019, at 7 a.m.
案發時間是 平成31年1月16日早上七點
JAPANESE SAKE
（日本清酒）
Hey. Who are you?
喂，你是誰啊？
Seventy thousand yen cash in the staff room was stolen
員工室內的現金七萬圓被搶
and the staff's injury will take two weeks to heal.
負傷店員花了兩週醫治才痊癒
After that, Takeo Tokachi, who lives nearby
而後住在附近的餐飲工讀生 十勝岳雄遭逮捕看押
The news says that he denied the charges.
新聞說他否認涉案吧？
Watch your manners.
你這樣很沒禮貌啦
-I didn't get to have lunch. -Serves you right.
-我沒吃午餐耶 -那是你自作自受
The duty solicitor who is here for an interview, I presume?
兩位是義務辯護律師吧？ 你們是來見十勝的？
Yes, we are.
是的
I'm CID's Matsumoto. I'm in charge of this case.
我是刑事課的人 負責這起案件，敝姓松本
I know it's the country system, but hats off to you.
雖說這是國家制度，但真令人敬佩啊
You have to make an effort to come and talk to the loser.
居然還特地來聽 那種無藥可救的傢伙說話
"Loser"?
無藥可救？
Tokachi is a notoriously bad guy.
十勝在這附近是有名的不良分子
Since his teens,
從十幾歲就好幾次 因為竊盜還有打架而接受輔導
Is his behavior so bad?
他平時行為就這麼偏差？
Yes, he was raised by his single mother,
是啊，畢竟是單親母子家庭
so maybe his family is problematic.
也有家庭上的問題吧
-But-- -But you can't say for sure.
-這… -這還說不準呢
Well, just talk to him for a bit.
總之，請隨便應付一下吧
I'm your lawyer, Kurokawa.
我是黑川律師
-I'm Wakura. Nice to meet you. -Nice to meet you.
-敝姓和倉，請多指教 -請多指教
-When will they let me go? -Yes?
-什麼時候會放我出去？ -什麼？
SUSPECT, TAKEO TOKACHI
（十勝岳雄，嫌疑人）
I'm innocent.
我是清白的
Hurry up and let me get out of here. That's why you're here, right?
快讓我出去，你們是為此而來的吧？
We can't do it immediately.
還沒辦法馬上讓你出去
First, we have to talk to you to see if you're the culprit--
要請你先說明事情經過 確認你不是犯人…
I didn't rob anyone!
就說我不是強盜了
I kept saying I didn't do it, but everyone just assumed I did.
我說了好幾次 但大家都硬要說是我做的
We don't assume that you did--
我們沒有預設立場…
I know you think I did it anyway!
反正你們也覺得是我做的吧
-We don't know yet. -What?
-這還不知道 -什麼？
We have no idea, so we have to investigate this.
就是因為不知道，所以才需要調查
What can you investigate?
到底要調查什麼？
I mean, lawyers are--
說來說去，我根本不相信律師…
Did you cut your finger with a knife?
你的手是菜刀割到的嗎？
You work part-time at a restaurant, right?
你在餐飲業打工吧？
I'm an apprentice chef.
我在當廚師學徒
I want to save some money and go to a culinary school.
我想存錢去上餐飲專門學校
I am sorry.
很抱歉
I am stupid.
我頭腦不好
So, when the police kept telling me
刑警一直要我認罪
to admit that I did it, I got worked up.
搞得我很火大
On January 16, at 7 a.m., when the robbery happened,
案發的1月16日早上七點
where were you?
你人在哪裡？
I don't remember the time,
時間我沒記得那麼清楚
but I traveled to my friend's by car the night before,
但前一天晚上我開車去朋友家
stopped by the petrol station in Hijiridai,
順道去了聖台的加油站
and I probably got home a bit after 7 a.m.
到家應該是七點出頭吧
Did you tell the police?
這有跟警方說嗎？
I told them, but they didn't believe me.
說了，但他們根本不相信
They said they'd investigate thoroughly and told me not to lie.
他們一直說 已經調查出結果了，要我別說謊
The petrol station ran on self-service at that time,
那時候是加油站的自助時間
so I didn't see anyone.
我也沒跟誰見面
That means there was no witness.
也沒有目擊證人對吧？
-Then… -What do you mean?
-那麼… -怎樣？
Are you saying that I did it?
你想說是我做的？
No…
不是…
Your attitude and the look on your face tell me clearly that
我說你啊，一臉看不起我的樣子
You really annoy me, so don't come again, bitch!
很讓人火大，別再來了，臭女人
Hey, it's over. Open the door.
喂，可以結束了，給我開門
What was that attitude? I'm sure that he did it.
那是什麼態度啊？肯定是他做的
I don't mean I agree with the detective, but he really is a loser.
雖然我不認同剛才的刑警 但他真是無藥可救
I don't know if he did it or not, but this is difficult.
還不知道他有沒有做
It isn't necessary. He told us not to come again.
沒必要吧，他也要我們別再來了
Excuse me. When can I see Takeo?
請問我什麼時候能見到岳雄呢？
Give me a break.
請你差不多一點
I've told you many times, he's only allowed to see his lawyer.
我已經說過很多次了 除了律師之外不能會面
-Excuse me. -You're right where I want you.
-請問… -來的正好
They are the lawyers.
這兩位就是辯護律師
I am Takeo Tokachi's mother.
我是十勝岳雄的母親
MUTSUMI TOKACHI SUSPECT'S MOTHER
（十勝睦美，嫌疑人母親）
Sorry for causing you trouble.
這次給兩位添麻煩了
It's okay.
沒這回事
It often rains here lately, but it'll stop very soon.
最近這附近常下雨 但通常很快就會停了
I'll make you some tea now.
我馬上去泡茶
No, it's okay.
不用麻煩了
We'd like to talk about your son.
比起這個，關於令郎的事…
I am sorry.
很抱歉
I heard he was rude to you.
他似乎對兩位很沒禮貌
No, it's fine.
不，這倒是無所謂
He denies the charges,
因為他否認犯行 所以可能會延長看押
I see.
這樣啊
May we have a look at your son's room?
能讓我們看一下令郎的房間嗎？
This way, please.
請跟我來
-Excuse me. -Okay.
-打擾了 -好
FOOD HYGIENE KITCHEN KNIVES FOR BEGINNERS
（《菜刀入門》）
CHATEAU - CUT INTO 6CM PIECES
（肉類切法）
They're photos from the past?
這是他以前的照片嗎？
Yes, they are.
是的
Sorry for being rude,
不好意思 我們聽說他被警方輔導了很多次
He was a delinquent in high school.
他在高中時學壞了
I raised him as a single mother,
因為我是單親媽媽，是我管教不周了
I don't think it's your fault.
我不認為這是您的責任
Does your son work part-time at another restaurant?
他沒在自家的店打工嗎？
It's a western restaurant in the neighboring town.
他是在隔壁町的西餐廳打工
He decided to be a cook.
他說要當廚師
I told him he could get trained at ours,
雖然我有跟他說 要實習在自家店裡就行了
but he said he wouldn't be able to be disciplined here.
但他卻說這樣會偷懶
He's been working hard and seriously.
看來他確實很認真呢
I don't think he's a loser, Miss Wakura.
看來並不是無藥可救啊，和倉律師
My son is really trying to turn over a new leaf,
那孩子是真的打算洗心革面
so he will never commit any robbery!
所以不可能犯下強盜案的
He denied it strongly too.
他本人也強烈否認，但是…
-But Mr. Kurokawa-- -I will make a request formally.
-但是黑川律師… -請容我鄭重地再次拜託您
Please… help Takeo!
拜託了，請幫幫岳雄
I beg you, Mr. Kurokawa!
拜託了，黑川律師
All right, then.
我明白了
I'll investigate it thoroughly and defend him.
我會徹底調查，奮戰到底
I am counting on you.
拜託了
Good evening.
辛苦了
-Good evening. -Welcome back.
-辛苦了 -歡迎回來
Miss Arima sent us some information about the case.
有馬小姐送案件情報來了
That's helpful.
幫上大忙了
I'm impressed by the power of the press.
媒體的力量果然厲害
Although she wanted another interview in exchange.
但她還是說要採訪你作為交換條件
I've read them and he seems guilty.
就目前看到的資料，嫌疑滿高的
He was caught on the security camera and he left his fingerprints.
有被現場監視器拍到，也留有指紋
On top of that, he has no alibi.
此外還沒有不在場證明
But Tokachi said he didn't do it.
但他本人說沒做
What was your first impression of him?
見面的印象如何？
Honestly, I think he did it.
老實說，我覺得是他做的
He got angry easily and his attitude was bad.
他個性很衝，態度也很差
But it doesn't mean that he committed the robbery.
但這也不代表他就是犯人啊
Well, you'll defend him before the prosecution,
這次是起訴前辯護
just break whatever reason
總之就先徹底調查被定罪的依據吧
Rather than winning the trial,
與其打官司，不如藉由不起訴而獲勝
Good evening.
辛苦了
Mr. Kurokawa and Miss Wakura, Mr. Beppu would like to see you.
所長要黑川律師跟和倉律師過去
Mr. Beppu?
所長？
Excuse me.
打擾了
Are you having supper?
您正在吃飯嗎？
Sorry.
抱歉
I heard that the corporate law colleagues had it for lunch.
聽說企業法務的人 中午吃了這個，害我也想吃了
Well, do sit down.
請坐
Well, Kittan's lunchbox is the best.
便當果然還是菊丹的好吃
The taste of tradition never changes.
不變的傳統美味
-I think it has changed. -What has?
-聽說變了 -什麼？
Please forget it. What would you like us to do?
沒事…您找我們有什麼事嗎？
Yes…
對了
You're in charge of a robbery-causing-injury case?
聽說這次是強盜傷害的辯護？
Yes. I hope I can do something before the prosecution.
對，可以的話 我希望在被起訴前做些什麼
About that.
關於這件事
I would like Miss Wakura to be in charge of the case.
我希望這次能讓和倉律師主導
-What? -What? I'll be in charge?
-什麼？ -什麼？我來主導嗎？
You helped Mr. Kurokawa last time and learned how to do criminal defense.
上次你協助黑川律師刑事辯護 應該也學到不少
This will let you gain experience.
這也是累積經驗的好機會 怎麼樣，黑川律師？
I don't mind.
我倒是無所謂
Okay, Miss Wakura will decide how to defend the client
好，那這次的辯護方針跟調查活動
I'm counting on you, Miss Wakura.
拜託你了，和倉律師 千萬別發生上次那種情況
Yes, Mr. Beppu.
我明白了
MITSUYA
（三津屋超商）
He had worked part-time at our store.
那傢伙曾在我們店裡打過工
He should know that there is only one staff member at that time too,
他也知道那時間店裡只有一個店員
that's why he did it.
所以才挑那時間下手吧
His face isn't shown clearly on the video.
從影片看來，並沒有清楚拍到臉
How do you know that it was Mr. Tokachi?
是怎麼斷定是十勝先生的呢？
It was just for a second, but I saw his masked face.
雖然只有一瞬間 但我有看到對方戴著口罩的臉
The eyes and the build looked like his.
眼睛跟體型都滿像的
-That means you didn't see it clearly? -I didn't,
-所以其實沒有看得很清楚？ -是這樣沒錯啦
but the police said they found his fingerprints.
但警方都說找到指紋了
His fingerprints were found at two places,
指紋有兩處
on the staff room's entrance door and at the store entrance.
在員工室的門跟出入口的門
But he left no fingerprint in the staff room, where cash was stolen.
但錢是從員工室被偷的 裡面卻沒留下指紋
Don't you think it's strange?
這不是很奇怪嗎？
He wore gloves in the staff room and took them off when he left.
警方認為他在員工室有戴手套
That's what the police thinks.
出來時脫掉了
-But that sounds far-fetched. -Of course it is.
-什麼啊？也太牽強附會了吧 -當然是牽強附會了
-Wow, they look delicious! -What are you doing?
-天啊，看起來真好吃 -你在做什麼啊？
What will Ms. Tokachi do now?
十勝屋之後會怎麼樣？
Close the restaurant and move, of course.
當然是關店搬家了 畢竟她兒子犯下那種案件
-Nothing's gone right for the lady. -Right.
-十勝太太還真慘啊 -是啊
I mean, the son she raised herself became a criminal.
靠自己一個女人 把兒子養大，卻變成了罪犯
Exactly.
就是說啊
Everything just makes me angry.
真讓人火大
The detective we met and the people at the store
會面時的那個刑警，還有超商的人
say it like the son commits crimes because Mrs. Tokachi is a single mom.
都說他是單親家庭才會學壞犯罪
Well, it can't be helped.
這也沒辦法啊
But assuming that he committed robbery is prejudice.
這樣就下判斷根本是偏見
He's a delinquent and committed robbery
說是單親家庭所以學壞
because he has a single mom. It's obvious.
學壞了才會犯下強盜案 這對一般人來說比較好懂啊
I never know what people say about us because of my son,
我也是不知道 會因為兒子而被人說些什麼
so I'm on edge very often.
所以總是戰戰兢兢的
Ms. Kinosaki, you're--
城崎小姐，你…
A single mother. It's a long story.
說來話長，我是單親母親
Did I let you down?
對我的看法變了嗎？
No, of course not.
沒這回事
This is the petrol station where Mr. Tokachi stopped by.
就是這裡，十勝先生順道去的加油站
I stopped by the petrol station at Hijiridai
順道去了聖台的加油站 到家應該是七點出頭吧
If they've kept the security camera's video
要是監視器有拍到 能藉此獲得不在場證明就好了
Wait. What is Mr. Kurokawa doing over there?
黑川律師在那裡做什麼？
Mr. Kurokawa!
黑川律師
Please don't do anything suspicious!
請別做些引人疑竇的事
No, this! I'm just curious about it.
不，是這個，我對這東西有點好奇
I wonder what it is used for.
不知道是用來做什麼的
I don't know!
天知道
Anyway, let's go and interview…
比起這個，先去打探情報吧
SELF-SERVICE NIRAYAMA OIL
（韮山石油，自助加油）
Oh? Mr. Kurokawa, fancy seeing you here.
黑川律師，還真巧啊
Hello.
你好
Mr. Ibusuki, are you investigating the robbery too?
指宿檢察官 你也在調查那起強盜傷害案嗎？
Yes, I am.
沒錯
Are you the prosecutor who called?
是先前打電話來的檢察官嗎？
I'm Ibusuki.
敝姓指宿
And the people there too?
這幾位也是嗎？
-We are lawyers. -Lawyer? Takeo's?
-我們是律師 -律師？岳雄的嗎？
What…
幹嘛？
-It is you! -What?
-果然是你 -什麼？
You're Mr. Tokachi's friend, right? I saw your photo in his room.
你是十勝先生的朋友吧？ 他的房間有你的照片
-I used to hang out with him. -Oh, right.
-我們以前確實是有一起混過 -是吧
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'd like to finish my job.
我想先處理事情
That's right. Sorry, please go ahead.
對喔，不好意思，請
Anyway, it's unusual
話說回來還真稀奇啊
for a prosecutor to go out to investigate a case.
檢察官居然會特地來現場調查
We also conduct investigations if necessary.
有必要時我們也會進行調查
In other words, the police's investigation alone wasn't enough?
也就是說，警方的搜查並不充分嗎？
Like Tokachi has an alibi?
或是找到十勝先生的不在場證明了？
Well, who knows?
天知道
The police came here too, right?
警察也有來這裡吧？
Yeah, they told me to show them the security camera footage.
是啊，他們要我 調監視器的影片出來看
They had a glance, took some photos, and left in a short time.
他們看了一下，拍完照片就離開了
Photos?
照片？
They didn't take any video tape
那群傢伙沒把影片帶回去
and only gave me this material for investigation.
只拍了照片當成搜查資料
Just two photos?
只有兩張照片？
Their investigation was quite careless.
調查得真鬆散啊
So you're here to properly check the video?
所以你才特地來確認影片？
-Can you find it? -It almost got deleted.
-如何？ -勉強有留下
Our security camera's video
我們店的監視器
is automatically updated every 150 hours.
每150小時就會自動更新一次
This was taken at 6:42 a.m. on the day of the robbery.
這是案發當天6點42分開始的影像
Here he is.
來了
He came at 6:45 a.m. and left at 6:49 a.m.
6點45分到，6點49分離開
It takes five minutes to go to the convenience store by car.
這裡距離案發超商有五分鐘車程
So, it's very possible for him to commit the robbery at 7 a.m.
也就是說，他完全有可能在七點犯案
But he ran away from the crime scene on foot, not by car.
犯人逃離案發現場時 似乎不是開車，而是徒步
He must've parked it nearby.
應該是停在附近了吧
But would someone who's going to rob refuel his car ten minutes before?
馬上就要搶劫的人 會在十分鐘前才加油嗎？
He might.
確實是有可能啊
Why? You think Takeo didn't do it, Mr. Lawyer?
律師先生，你認為岳雄沒犯案嗎？
I don't know. That's why I'm investigating.
不知道，所以才要調查
I know him very well.
我很清楚那傢伙的事
He's my friend, so I don't want to say this,
我們是死黨，我也不想這樣說 但我認為他就是犯人
He always says he wants money.
因為他總是嚷著想要錢
Mr. Ibusuki, are you going to prosecute my client?
指宿檢察官 你打算起訴這起案件嗎？
No comment.
不予置評
This time, the police
這次警方很明顯 是在推測搜查的情況下逮捕嫌疑人
You can't identify the person on the video
超商的監視器影片
taken at the convenience store.
也無法直接確認犯人
Mr. Kurokawa,
黑川律師
innocent until proven guilty is only a principle.
“當證據無法產生有罪之確信 即應認定無罪”只是原則
Your father taught me that all suspects are suspected for a reason.
令尊教我的是“有嫌疑 就表示有足以被懷疑的依據”
It's your job to consider the interests of the suspect or accused.
考慮嫌疑人跟被告的利益 是你們的職責
If you want me to drop the prosecution,
若想爭取不起訴 就請準備好充分的證據
-Mr. Kurokawa. -I am really curious about that.
-那個，黑川律師… -那東西還是很讓人好奇啊
But that rubbish isn't related to the case.
那種破銅爛鐵跟案子無關吧
This is Mr. Todoroki, who created this Sunrise Tower.
這位就是製作這座日出塔的轟木先生
MASTER AT WORK IN WEST TAMA SUNRISE TOWER
（西多摩匠人，自家的日出塔）
Excuse me. Why did you make this tower?
請問您製作這座塔的原因是什麼呢？
The sun rises from where my house faces every morning,
我們家的方位 每天早上都可以看到太陽升起
then an idea flashed across my mind one day…
某天我看著那景象，突然靈機一動…
What a man.
好誇張的人
It'd be great to have a tower that shines when the sun rises.
如果能做一座塔 接收日出的陽光就好了
The place of sunrise changes,
日出的位置會變
so I adjust it every day to make it reflect the light beautifully.
所以我每天都會調整 讓這座塔能好好反射陽光
Sunrise Tower?
原來是日出塔啊
I'm happy that I got an answer.
總算痛快多了
It's a story reported by our breakfast show three years ago.
這是我們電視台三年前拍的資訊節目
What's wrong with it?
怎麼了嗎？
It's just Mr. Kurokawa's personal interest.
這只是黑川律師的個人興趣
It has nothing to do with the case.
跟案件無關
Somehow she's worked up.
她似乎很緊繃啊
Is the convenience store robbery not going well?
超商強盜案不順利嗎？
It's only a quick investigation,
我們大概調查了一下 還沒查到能當作辯護素材的事實
The public prosecutor is likely to prosecute our client.
檢察官很有可能直接起訴
We haven't got much time left to get him to drop the prosecution.
能爭取不起訴的時限也逐漸逼近了
Exactly!
就是說啊
So, we don't have time for you to fool around, Mr. Kurokawa.
所以沒時間像黑川律師你這樣亂搞了
But I'm not fooling around.
我沒在亂搞啊
Oh… It is shining over here too.
這裡也有反光呢
You totally are fooling around.
根本就是在亂搞
I've reserved a lot of time for you today too.
今天也有很多時間
Be prepared for it.
你做好覺悟吧
MASTER AT WORK IN WEST TAMA - AT HOME
（西多摩匠人，自家的日出塔）
Mr. Kurokawa, I'd like to talk to you about our plan for the case.
黑川律師 我想跟你討論接下來的作戰策略
Miss Wakura, have a look at this.
和倉律師，請看一下這個
It's reflecting the rising sun's light. So?
這是早晨陽光的反射吧 又怎麼了嗎？
The sun rose at 6:45 a.m. on January 16,
案發當天 1月16日的日出是6點45分
It's right at this time,
剛好就是這個時間
but don't you think the light is weaker than the one in the show?
跟電視台拍攝時的影片相比 不覺得光比較弱嗎？
So what?
那又怎樣？
Also, the light here seems to be moving.
還有這個光，總覺得好像在動啊
I just find it strange.
我覺得有點奇怪
You're wasting my time. Come at once.
別浪費時間了，請馬上過來
Mr. Tokachi's mother just called.
十勝先生的母親剛才打電話來了
She would like you to go to the convenience store at once.
似乎想請你們馬上趕去案發超商
The crime scene?
去案發現場？
The police have conducted an investigation.
-就說警方已經調查出結果了 -請再調查一次…
Oh, lawyers! Do something about her!
律師先生 請你們幫忙應付一下這位太太
What's the matter?
怎麼了嗎？
I've been looking for the receipt my son got at the petrol station,
我找了一下那孩子 去加油站的發票有沒有留下來
then I found these.
結果找到了這些
-Receipts issued by this store? -Yes.
-是這間超商的發票？ -對
My son buys things here from time to time.
那孩子偶爾會來這裡買東西
So, the fingerprints lifted might be left when he came as a customer?
也就是說，警方採集到的指紋 也有可能是來買東西時沾上的
So, I would like to check the videos taken by the security camera.
對，所以我希望 店家能讓我確認一下監視器影片
But we…
就算你這麼說…
We won't interrupt your work.
不會妨礙你們工作的
Please let us check them in the presence of a lawyer.
請在我們律師的陪同下 讓她進行確認吧，拜託了
Please let us check them!
拜託了
Oh! This is Takeo!
這就是岳雄
The video was taken two days before the robbery.
這是案發兩天前的影像
Whether the fingerprints lifted here is relevant or not is now dubious.
就是從這扇門採集到的指紋 被當成犯案嫌疑證據
Excuse me. I have to go now.
那個…我先失陪了，有事請找店員吧
Thank you, sir.
謝謝
It must be tough for you, ma'am,
不過太太你還真辛苦啊 被兒子搞得團團轉
I am sorry for bringing you so much trouble.
很抱歉，給您添麻煩了
I guess it really doesn't work out if you aren't related by blood.
我看是這樣吧 沒血緣關係就是管教不來
Actually…
那孩子原本是遠房親戚的孩子
He was abused by his biological parents,
他被親生父母虐待
so I adopted him when he was three years old.
三歲時由我收養
When Takeo first came to live with me,
岳雄來到我家的時候
I was really happy.
我真的很高興
When I saw him enjoying
看著那孩子吃我做的飯
the meal I cooked for him,
吃得津津有味
I was really happy.
真的讓我好開心
It is true that…
岳雄學壞了
Takeo became a delinquent and caused many people trouble
給人添了麻煩的確是事實
and maybe the way I raised him was wrong,
或許是我管教無方
but the boy really tried to turn over a new leaf!
但是那孩子是真的打算洗心革面
On the day of the robbery,
案發當天的早上也是
I saw him when he got home in the morning.
我有看到岳雄早上回家時的臉
If he was guilty of something,
要是他有做什麼壞事 我看他的臉就知道了
We have been mother and son for 18 years.
畢竟我們也當了18年的母子
You've done so many evil deeds, do you think you can start again?
做了那麼多壞事還妄想重新來過？
The restaurant you work part-time at has fired you.
你打工的西餐廳已經把你開除了
-What? -Even your mother doesn't trust you.
-什麼？ -你母親也不相信你
You're ruining your mother's life!
是你毀掉了你母親的人生
Hey! Stop it!
快住手
What are you doing? Hey! Stop it!
怎麼了？喂，快住手
-Stop it! What are you doing? -Stop it now!
-快住手 -你做什麼啊？快住手
Found it!
有了，這樣就能立證 說指紋不是案發時留下的
Thank you! So, Takeo--
謝謝，那岳雄就…
No, I don't think this alone can clear him of suspicion.
不，光是這樣沒辦法洗清嫌疑
Mr. Tokachi hasn't got an alibi himself.
還是沒找到 十勝先生本人的不在場證明
No.
怎麼這樣？
Wakura speaking.
是，我是和倉
Not yet.
不，還沒
What?
什麼？
Why were you so reckless?
為什麼這麼亂來？
I am just…
我開始越來越迷惘
The detective accused me of it every day…
刑警每天都在跟我逼供
and I heard that the restaurant fired me.
聽說餐廳也開除我了
I just…
我想…
I wanted to free myself from the torture.
我想乾脆一死了之
Free yourself from the torture?
一死了之？
I really wanted to turn over a new leaf
我真的是想洗心革面的
because it would make my mom happy.
我想讓老媽開心
But now…
但是已經…
Is it already too late?
我在想是不是已經太遲了
Your mother believes that you are innocent.
令堂相信你是清白的
Does she really?
是嗎？真的嗎？
Why do you say that?
你這話什麼意思？
Because…
因為…
she is…
她…
You think she won't trust you because you aren't related by blood?
因為不是親生的 所以你覺得她不會相信你？
Don't be such a baby!
別說這種軟弱的話了
Saying you have a single mom or used to be a delinquent
是單親家庭又怎樣？ 曾經學壞又怎樣？
or not related by blood really annoys me!
不是親生的又怎樣？煩死人了
The important thing is if you're a decent person now!
最重要的是現在 現在的你到底願不願意振作
Your mother trusts you.
別因為自己的處境艱難 就懷疑深信著你的母親
I'm sorry I shouted at him.
很抱歉，我居然那樣大吼
It's okay. What you said was right.
不，和倉律師你說的沒錯
My mom is a single mother too.
我家也是單親家庭
I didn't want people to look down on us,
為了不讓人瞧不起 我拼命讀書當上律師
So, it got me worked up.
不由得就對這種情況感到煩躁
I think it's brilliant.
我覺得你很了不起
But I think you're contradicting yourself a bit.
但也覺得有點矛盾
Contradicting?
矛盾？
You don't want people to look down on you because of your mom.
因為是單親家庭 所以不想被人瞧不起
That means you accept people's views
這就代表了自己也接受了 單親家庭被人瞧不起的價值觀
It is only a prejudice.
明明都只是偏見
You are a decent person now.
現在是否有好好振作
That's all that matters.
這才是最重要的
Thanks for coming at such a late hour.
抱歉，這種時間還找你們來
He brought us much trouble for causing chaos in his cell.
因為他在拘留所引發騷動 搞得我們也很困擾
He was pretty cornered during the questioning.
看來你們在偵訊時把他逼得滿緊的啊
This is our job.
這就是我們的工作
Moreover, the prosecutor decided to charge him.
而且檢方似乎也決定起訴了
But everything is just circumstantial evidence!
怎麼會？不都只是狀況證據嗎？
Say it to the public prosecutor.
這請你去跟檢方說
He'll be prosecuted?
起訴啊…
We have to take action!
這樣下去就糟糕了啊
It might not work,
雖然很難
but we should try using what we have, including the fingerprints,
但包括指紋 就現有材料爭取公訴取消比較好吧
Gosh!
真是的
-Please let me borrow this. -Who are you?
-那個…請借我一下 -你是誰啊？
I heard the corporate law colleagues had it for lunch,
聽說企業法務的人 中午吃了這個，害我也想吃了
It's been raining often lately,
最近這附近常下雨
but it usually stops very soon.
但通常很快就會停了
What are you doing, Mr. Kurokawa?
黑川律師，你在做什麼？
What time is it?
現在幾點？
It's 6:25 p.m.
6點25分
Maybe I'll make it in time.
或許還趕得上
Thank you.
謝謝
Wait! Where are you going?
等等，你要去哪裡？
Mr. Kurokawa!
黑川律師
What…
等等
Please tell me what you are doing.
請你說明情況
The solar azimuth angle is minus 63 degrees.
太陽方位角負63度 鏡面往東邊移2度
Okay.
好
Dr. Akiu!
秋保先生
-Like this? -Yes.
-這樣嗎？ -對…
Oh, you're here too?
你也來了啊？
What are you doing here at such a late hour?
這時間在這種地方做什麼？
I asked Dr. Akiu to analyze the video taken by
我請秋保先生 幫我分析了加油站監視器影像
Analyze it? But why?
分析？為什麼？
Oh, it's coming.
要來了
All right.
好
This is art.
真是藝術
Wow, you have a sharp mind.
你真內行啊
I'll make you some tea. Wait here.
我現在就去泡茶，你等等
Dr. Akiu, about the light in the video…
秋保先生
You've realized too?
你也察覺到了嗎？
Probably…
原因恐怕…
that's what caused it.
就是那個
I knew it!
果然
Mr. Kurokawa! I don't get what you're talking about at all!
黑川律師 我完全聽不懂是怎麼回事啊
Dr. Akiu, please explain it to me!
秋保教授，拜託你說明一下
Hey! I've made some tea. Come in and warm yourself up!
喂，我泡了茶，進屋裡暖暖身子吧
I won't explain it. First, I'll go and have tea.
我拒絕說明，先喝茶吧
Gosh!
真是的
Really? Are you sure?
真的嗎？你確定嗎？
I am sure, but who on earth are you?
確定是確定啦，但你到底是誰？
Mr. Kurokawa, what is going on?
黑川律師，到底是怎麼回事？
Miss Wakura, we might be able to get Mr. Tokachi's alibi now!
和倉律師，這樣或許 就能確立十勝先生的不在場證明了
Yes, one vehicle each. Please make the arrangement.
沒錯，各一台，那就麻煩了
Is this okay?
沒問題嗎？
Mr. Senami is keeping an eye on us. If we don't tell him…
你平時就被盯上了 又在沒告知局長的情況下擅自…
It's okay.
無所謂，黑川手上的案子 我得盡量追才行
SUN'S POSITION, SUNRISE TOWER PETROL STATION, PLASTIC TENT
（溫室，太陽方位 日出塔，加油站）
-Good evening.
-辛苦了
You are here again?
又來了啊？
He doesn't even say hello.
真親切的招呼啊
I'll interview him, but I got him what he needs in return.
作為採訪的交換條件 需要的東西我都準備好了
-Where? -The light is in the car.
-在哪裡？ -燈具都在車裡
The vehicles will arrive soon.
其他車輛馬上過來
You can at least say thank you.
至少也道個謝吧
Good.
好
The vehicles are here.
車來了
He'll do a large-scale experiment this time too?
這次也這麼大陣仗？
Is this okay?
這樣如何？
It's 0.5 degrees too low. Raise it one meter higher.
還差0.5度，再抬高一公尺試試看
Listen, sunrise isn't what we'll re-enact.
聽好了，要重現的並不是日出
Okay.
是
Please raise it one meter higher!
再提高一公尺
It's now at the same angle as it was on January 16.
已經吻合1月16日的角度了
Good.
好，等我下指示就打開吧
Okay.
是
-Let's begin. -Okay.
-要開始了 -是
Will it really go smoothly?
真的會順利嗎？
It will. Let's go and stand by.
沒問題的，開始準備吧
Okay.
是
All right.
好
Wakura, turn on the valve.
和倉，開始放水
Turn off the valve.
停止放水
The experiment is done.
驗證完畢
-It's the same. -Yes, it's the same.
-一樣 -真的一樣呢
We took the video when we did the experiment last night.
這是昨晚的驗證影像
If you compare it with the video taken at the petrol station
請把這個跟案發當天 加油站的影像相比較
you can see that the light flickers in both videos.
如你所見，兩邊的影像都有光影搖曳
So, what's your point?
然後呢？這又怎樣？
I don't know what you want to prove by showing me this.
突然給我看這些影像，我也莫名其妙
We'll say our conclusion.
直接說結論
The video gives Mr. Tokachi a valid alibi.
這影像可以確立 十勝先生的不在場證明
The time here shows that Mr. Tokachi was caught on camera at 6:45 a.m.,
拍到十勝先生的時間
but the actual time was 7 a.m.
但實際上是七點的影像
It was the exact same time when the convenience store was robbed.
-什麼？ -跟超商強盜案發生時是相同時間
He was definitely at the petrol station at that time.
那時他確實在加油站
The time shown on the video taken by the petrol station's camera
加油站監視器的時間 比實際時間晚15分鐘
The camera is old and isn't well maintained.
沒維修的老舊監視器若沒定期確認
it might do the recording with the wrong time shown.
似乎也有記錄錯誤時間的可能
I can't believe this.
若沒有明確依據的話 這很難讓人相信
The flickering of the light you saw is the evidence.
依據就是剛才請你看的光影搖曳現象
The phenomenon is caused by
引起這現象的
the rain water collected on
是加油站旁邊溫室累積的雨水
Sunlight was focused by the rain water
雨水累積造成的光
reflected by the mirror and shone on the tower.
反射到鏡子上，照亮了日出塔
HEIGHT OF THE SUN
（日出塔，鏡子，溫室）
On the day of the robbery,
案發當天早上 該地區發生了集中性暴雨
This video was taken by the security camera at the plastic tent that day.
這就是設置在 溫室的監視器當天的影像
As you can see, the time shown is 7 a.m.
如你所見，時間是早上七點
You mean when the man did this, it caused the flickering of light
你是說這個行為 引發加油站影像中的光影搖曳？
It isn't enough to convince me to accept your claim that the time
但要藉此證明加油站監視器時間有誤
of the petrol station's video is wrong.
似乎有點牽強
Why is that?
為什麼？
You say water caused the light to flicker.
積水造成了光影搖曳
Fine, I'll accept it.
這點我可以認同
But wind or other things could've caused the light to flicker too.
但積水晃動也有可能 是由風或其他原因引起
Maybe the time of the petrol station's security camera is right
也許就如加油站監視器時間所示
and it's also possible that the light flickered at 6:45 a.m.--
此現象就是在6點45分引起的…
It isn't possible.
不可能
Definitely.
絕對不可能
You'll say for sure?
你說得真果斷啊
If you play the videos taken at both places at 6:45 a.m. together,
只要把加油站跟溫室的影像
It started to rain in the plastic tent's video,
溫室這邊下了雨
but it wasn't at the petrol station next to it.
但旁邊的加油站卻沒下雨
This is the data of the local weather on the day of the robbery.
這是案發當天該區域的氣象資料
There was localized torrential downpour
集中性暴雨
from 6:50 a.m. to 6:55 a.m.
是6點50分起的五分鐘內發生的
But it isn't raining in the petrol station's video
而此降雨 在加油站的畫面中並沒有拍到
because the rain had stopped.
因為當時雨已經停了
Without a doubt, Mr. Tokachi was at the petrol station at 7 a.m.
七點的時候
It wasn't possible for him to rob the convenience store.
他不可能在超商犯下強盜案
The witness' testimony wasn't clear.
目擊證詞不明確 我們也驗證過超商監視器影像
and can prove that
可以證明十勝先生的指紋 是於案發前沾上的
FINGERPRINT ANALYSIS REPORT
（強盜傷害案指紋鑑定書）
PHOTO 1 - NEAR STAFF ROOM ENTRANCE DOOR
（員工室門口附近）
-Check this. -Yes, sir.
-把這拿去對照 -是
Based on the suspect's family background
這是基於嫌疑人的家庭環境
and his bad behavior before, the police were biased
以及過往不良紀錄之偏見
and they arrested my client wrongly.
警方的不當逮捕
In this robbery-causing-injury case,
這次的強盜傷害案件
Mr. Takeo Tokachi…
十勝岳雄先生…
is innocent, without a doubt.
絕對是清白的
Who is the robber, then?
那麼犯人是誰？
The police or you have to investigate this.
這是警方或你們應該調查的
This isn't our job.
不是我們的職責
Well…
那個…
Thank you for helping me.
真的很感謝你們
Don't mention it. We're glad your innocence is proven.
不會，能證明無罪真是太好了
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Well…
沒什麼
I'm just wondering if I can still work at a restaurant.
只是不知道今後 我們家的店是否還能繼續開下去
It's my fault that I've done many stupid things.
雖然是我不好，過去做了太多蠢事
People's opinion about me must've gotten worse after this too.
但這次的事肯定又讓評價更差了
-Well… -Frankly, I think it'll be tough.
-這… -老實說，我想應該會有點難
If people had been dubious about you once,
面對曾被懷疑的人
they'll be prejudiced, and you can't do anything about it.
就算招致偏見也無可奈何
Mr. Tokachi, although you're innocent this time,
十勝先生，雖然你這次是清白的 但你過往確實素行不良
That's why you were suspected.
所以才會被人懷疑
-Mr. Kurokawa! -But…
-黑川律師 -但是
I believe that people can change.
我相信人是可以改變的
If you want to change people's prejudice,
若想顛覆別人的偏見
please prove that you have changed yourself.
就請靠自己來證明吧
You're right.
也是
Your mother is waiting for you.
令堂在等著你呢
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
I'm home.
我回來了
Welcome home.
歡迎回來
There aren't many customers today.
今天沒什麼客人呢
-Mom, I-- -Sit down.
-老媽，我… -快坐下
You must be starving.
肚子餓了吧？
Dig in.
快吃吧
Come on.
來
Here you go.
快吃
Just think about
今後的事
what you're going to do later.
吃飽再來想吧
It's tasty.
真好吃
Oh, I'm hungry.
肚子餓了
I've got lunch when we return to the office.
回事務所就有便當能吃了
I can't walk.
我不行了
Isn't it a lot of bother to cook every time?
每次都自己做便當不會很費力嗎？
My family is poor, so I don't like to eat out.
我家很窮，而且我不習慣吃外食
Eat out.
外食啊
I haven't eaten out lately.
最近完全沒吃外食呢
But you chose to be poor yourself, didn't you?
黑川律師 你會這麼窮是自己選擇的吧？
You come from a rich family.
明明是好人家出身的
Your father is a high official at the prosecutors' office, right?
令尊是菁英檢察官吧？
But we don't really stay in touch.
不過我跟他幾乎沒來往了
Why did you become a lawyer?
你到底為什麼會當律師啊？
And you specialize in criminal defense,
而且還專門接這種不賺錢的刑事案件
Both your clothes and lifestyle are so casual and sloppy.
服裝跟生活都鬆散到不行
Thinking an elite prosecutor's son has to be decent
認為菁英檢察官之子 就會很可靠，這可是偏見
Please don't avoid my question.
別蒙混過去了 這是對令尊的反抗嗎？
Rebellious?
反抗啊…
If you say so, maybe I am.
或許是這樣沒錯
Because he thinks that people can never change.
因為
On January 18,
本月18日在旭市發生的超商強盜案
the MPD arrested the suspect, 21-year-old Yuji Nirayama,
警方經調查 逮捕了旭市一加油站之店員
who works at a petrol station in Asahi City,
嫌疑人韮山雄二，21歲 以強盜傷害嫌疑遭逮捕
He had intended to frame Tokachi for it right from the start.
他似乎從一開始 就想讓十勝先生背黑鍋
He knew Tokachi had been out that day
他早就知道十勝先生那天會出門 還特地模仿他的穿著
But they were friends, right?
但他們原本不是朋友嗎？
Then, why…
為什麼要這樣做？
It was because he was jealous.
聽說動機是出於嫉妒
He and Tokachi used to be delinquents.
過去一起做壞事的十勝先生
Tokachi had a dream and has turned over a new leaf,
找到了夢想，打算洗心革面
but he is still living without a goal.
自己卻還是整天無所事事
How selfish of him!
真是自私，太過分了
By the way, where are Kurokawa and Mr. Yufuin today?
話說回來 今天黑川跟湯布院先生呢？
Mr. Kurokawa is looking for food in his room
黑川律師在房間裡找東西吃
and Mr. Yufuin is--
湯布院律師他…
Summoned by Mr. Beppu and is at his office.
被所長叫去了
Although the defense went well,
雖說辯護順利
frankly, I can't be happy…
但我沒辦法打從心裡感到高興
if he does whatever he pleases every single time.
每次都這麼亂來
I am sorry.
很抱歉
But he needed to do the experiment to win.
但為了獲勝，驗證是必要的
Mr. Yufuin.
湯布院律師
I'll make it clear to you.
老實說，你是我的眼中釘
And your successor, Kurokawa, too.
而你的繼承人黑川也是
KITTY DINER
（貓咪食堂）
This is impossible, even for me.
再怎麼說這也吃不下吧
Okay.
好吧
I know it's done for evidence, but isn't the scale too big?
說是驗證，也太大費周章了吧
It can't be helped.
這也沒辦法 扯上秋保先生通常就是這樣
Who is Dr. Akiu actually?
請問秋保先生到底是何方神聖啊？
He's been bossy and taking the lead.
上次跟這次都一臉高傲地鎮壓全場
I didn't tell you?
我沒說過嗎？
Dr. Akiu was Mr. Kurokawa's senior at Touo University.
秋保副教授跟黑川律師 是東央大學的學長學弟
His senior?
學長學弟？
Kurokawa did science and technology at first,
黑川原本在理工學部
but he went to study law in his third year and became a lawyer.
大三時才轉到法學部成為律師
From science and technology to law.
從理工學部轉到法學部
Mr. Kurokawa has been weird since he was in college.
黑川律師從大學時代就是個怪人啊
Not exactly weird.
與其說是怪人
His personality just changed at that time.
不如說是那時變了一個人 他的情況應該是這樣
MURDER BY TOUO UNIVERSITY STUDENT
（東央大學生殺人案 被告處無期徒刑）
Yes!
太好了
THIS DRAMA IS FICTITIOUS
（本劇純屬虛構）
A medical accident happened at a hospital.
在白色巨塔發生的醫療事故
Our daughter's life was taken suddenly.
女兒的性命突然被奪走
Can you understand how we feel?
你們明白當父母的是什麼心情嗎？
Proving someone's innocence can't bring a dead person back to life.
就算經過實證，洗清了冤屈 死者也不會復生
But the lawyers still use the power of science to find out the truth.
即使如此 律師們仍想以科學手段找出真相
We claim his innocence.
辯護人主張無罪
Have you reported this?
這件事我也有跟上層報告
It's total nonsense.
這根本是亂寫一通啊
This is to change the hospital.
是為了改變這間醫院
I'll investigate thoroughly and defend you.
我會徹底調查，奮戰到底
-Don't take this case. -Aren't you going to go to someone?
-收手吧 -我們到底該恨誰才好？
It can't operate itself.
光是說著 “總有一天要改變”是不行的
A problem has occurred, so it has to be changed.
必須打從發生問題的這個當下 就做出改變才行